Philip Singer Papers
Philip Singer Papers
- Research files
  - Hypnosis
    - Recordings
      - Hypnotic Strategies / Talking in Trance, singer_p_0718; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Self Hypnosis / Guided Imagery, singer_p_0798; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 49)
      - Self Hypnosis = Stress Reduction; Deepening Self Hypnosis, singer_p_0612; label on tape reads, "Waking state and talking in France"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
      - Self-Hypnosis: Age Regression for Ego Strength, singer_p_0646; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Indian medicine, 1960-1963 (Box 12)
  - Indigenous healers
    - Indigenous Healers, SAA Conference, 1972/04/05; singer_p_0544; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Indigenous Healers, SAA Conference, 1972/04/05; singer_p_0545; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Indigenous Healers, SAA Conference, 1972/04/05; singer_p_0546; the label reads, "audience reacts"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Institute of American Indian Arts, Radicals and Renegades, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Iroquois False Face Society, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Italy
    - NICU, 1984-1989 (Box 12)
    - NICU, mammography, 1985 (Box 12)
    - NICU, National Perinatal Information Center, 1988-1991 (Box 12)
    - NICU, Which Babies Shall Live?: Humanistic Dimensions of the Care of Imperiled Newborns, Thomas H. Murray and Arthur L. Caplan, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Recordings
      - NICU #4, 1989/01/20; singer_p_1502; handwritten text on side of case reads, "good visuals"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 57)
        An itemized list of film contents is written on side of case. It reads, "'Madonnas and child,' Jordano and parents, location scenes, aides / repairs / equipment, weight scale, cleaning incubators / radio, doctor / nurse chart interaction, bottle feeding in incubator, doctor and parents."
      - Italy, NICU, 02/11/1989; singer_p_0449; Hi8; running time 15:00 (Box 47)
        Label on container reads, "Mammography (first day), reception - writing, x-rays, Dr. Roselli, exams, echo, aspiration."
      - Italy, NICU [Tape 1], 01/17/1989; singer_p_0441; Hi8; running time 60:00 (Box 47)
        Label on tape reads, "Santo Bono - AM/PM." Label on container reads, "PM - Dr Mancini; Hx location - inside/outside; Interviews with Ruggierd/Jourdand; PM intensive care Dr Mancini - Nxs."
      - Italy, NICU [Tape 2], 01/19/1989; singer_p_0442; Hi8; running time 60:00 (Box 47)
        Label on tape reads, "Messina and Jordano." Label on container reads, "Messina and Jordano; Messina fixes machines; broncoscope begins; "Minna talks to Nxs; Telephone; Nxs station; Worker repairs equipment; Primario; Waiting families; Messina and Jordano; Mother and discharged baby; location outside Hx; Nxs make supplies; broncoscopy. "
      - Italy, NICU [Tape 3], 01/19/1989; singer_p_0443; label on container reads, "Nxs work; broncoscopy; NICU - Messina/Jordano; Jordano operates; close ups; Nx trainees; Jordano/parents nxs work"; Hi8; running time 60:00 (Box 47)
      - Italy, NICU [Tape 5], 01/20/1989; singer_p_0444; label on container reads, "Messina PM, outside hx"; Hi8; running time 20:00 (Box 47)
      - Italy, NICU [Tape 6], 01/26/1989; singer_p_0445; label on container reads, "Clean babies, outside Nx station; FM talks to parent phone"; Hi8; running time 20:00 (Box 47)
      - Italy, NICU [Tape 7], 01/26/1989; singer_p_0446; label on container reads, "Parents - gatekeeper, hx chapel, empty in cub, dxs - baby on table; drinking expresso; parents inside - good visual"; Hi8; running time 20:00 (Box 47)
      - Italy, NICU [Tape 8], 01/26/1989; singer_p_0447; label on container reads, "Santo Buno, last 30 minutes, good visuals, parents inside"; Hi8; running time 20:00 (Box 47)
      - Italy, NICU [Tape 8], 02/11/1989; singer_p_0448; label on container reads, "Last 10-15 minutes, parents [enter into sofa?]"; Hi8; running time 15:00 (Box 47)
  - Japan, "Marriage in Japan, Conformity, and Diversity: Comparisons of Japan and United States," Betty Lanham, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Jewish cemetaries, 1999-2000 (Box 12)
  - Jewish ghettos and holocaust, 1997-2000; articles (Box 13)
  - Kahlo, Frida
    - Frida Kahlo: Artistic Therapy Group, singer_p_0901; DVD; running time 20:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Frida Kahlo: Artistic Therapy Group, singer_p_0902; DVD; running time 20:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Frida Kahlo: Artistic Therapy Group, singer_p_1237; Spanish with English subtitles; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 6)
    - Frida Kahlo: Narrative Therapy in Brooklyn, NY, singer_p_0903; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Frida Kahlo: Narrative Therapy in Brooklyn, NY, singer_p_1169; DVD; running time 20:00 (Oversize 5)
    - Frida Terapia, Chapter 8, singer_p_1275; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 6)
    - Grupo de Terapia Artistico, Frida Kahlo, singer_p_1426; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
    - Kahlo #1, November 21, 2005; singer_p_0146; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 36)
    - Kahlo #2, singer_p_0147; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 36)
    - Kahlo #3, singer_p_0148; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 36)
    - Kahlo #4, singer_p_0149; label on box reads, "Depression, suicide"; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 36)
    - Kahlo #4 Suicide, 2005; singer_p_0354; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
    - Kahlo #8, singer_p_1377; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 54)
    - Kahlo #11, 2006/03/27; singer_p_1376; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 54)
    - Kahlo #11, Anger, 2006; singer_p_0355; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
    - Kahlo #11, Anger, 2006; singer_p_0356; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
    - Kahlo #12 Santeria, Spirited, 2006; singer_p_0353; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
    - Kahlo #13 Espiditista and Mental Health, 2006/04/10; singer_p_1379; DVD; running time 46:00 (Box 54)
    - Kahlo #14 Last, singer_p_1378; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 54)
    - Kahlo Moma, 2006/05/01; singer_p_1191; DVD; running time 30:00 (Oversize 5)
  - Kali cult therapeutic rituals in Guyana, undated (Box 13)
  - Kali Mari, "She Who is God, Prayers to Kali Mari," Hinduis Today, Jun 1995 (Box 23)
  - Kali, sexual assault in India, 2013-2015 (Box 13)
  - KOK
    - KOK WGY Radio Interview, 1979; singer_p_0757; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
    - KOK WGY Radio Interview, 1979; singer_p_0758; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
    - KOK WGY Radio Interview (Duplicate), 1979; singer_p_0760; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
    - KOK: Bone Mender, Oba Village, Elephant Horn Reception, singer_p_0772; Philip Singer response; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
    - KOK: WWJ Radio Interview, Traditional Healing and Godianism, 1978; singer_p_0773; Audio cassette; running time 15:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Korea
    - Dr. P. Singer in Korea, singer_p_1233; addresses cupping, herbs, and constitutional medicine; DVD; running time 25:00 (Oversize 6)
    - Dr. P. Singer in Korea, singer_p_1236; addresses cupping, herbs, and constitutional medicine; DVD; running time 25:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Lagos
    - Lagos, 1977/08/04; singer_p_0745; label reads, "OB-GYN chants baby out; interview with pregnant women; interview with chief 'your health is my business'"; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
    - Lagos, 1977/08/07; singer_p_0746; label reads, "Lunatic ikorodu; Dr. Tella-Lambo U-Lagos"; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
    - Lagos, 1977/08/03; singer_p_0747; label reads, "Walk in Laribois Gardens with research committee; Chief Lawonson and patients"; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
    - Lagos, 1977/08/07; singer_p_0748; label reads, "Lunatics ikorodu; wrong speed"; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
    - Lagos, 1977/08/09; singer_p_0749; label reads, "Lambo interview in house; Esho picks herbs; bone mender"; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
    - Lagos, 1977/08/03; singer_p_0750; label reads, "Walk with Chief Lambo and research in Lambo herbal garden, discussion [of] 9 herbs"; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
    - Lagos, 1977/08/02; singer_p_0751; label reads, "Sync interview w/p Singer on Posrch [this previous line is crossed out], also herbal healing market"; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
    - Lagos, 1977/08/02; singer_p_0752; label reads, "Medical herbalist meeting, interview blind supreme head"; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Lakota Sioux Native Americans
    - Snapshots in Complexity: The Lakota Sioux of South Dakota, singer_p_1194; DVD; running time 106:00 (Oversize 5)
    - Snapshots in Complexity: The Lakota Sioux of South Dakota, singer_p_1289; DVD; running time 106:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Lansing
    - [Lansing] [Illegible], 1994; singer_p_1501; VHS: VHS-C; running time 70:00 (Box 57)
    - [Lansing] Greece Ouzerie, 1994; singer_p_1500; VHS: VHS-C; running time 70:00 (Box 57)
    - [Lansing] Haiti (1 of 1), 1995/05/05; singer_p_1498; VHS: VHS-C; running time 70:00 (Box 57)
    - [Lansing] Haiti, Carla, Wanita (1 of 2), 1995/04/21; singer_p_1496; VHS: VHS-C; running time 84:00 (Box 57)
    - [Lansing] Haitian (2 of 2), 1995/04/21; singer_p_1497; VHS: VHS-C; running time 70:00 (Box 57)
    - [Lansing] Pierre Antoine, Lansing, Haiti, 1995/07/18; singer_p_1495; VHS: VHS-C; running time 120:00 (Box 57)
    - [Lansing] PVS Interview, 1995; singer_p_1499; VHS: VHS-C; running time 70:00 (Box 57)
  - Magic
    - "Magic: A Theoretical Reassesment," Michael Winkelman, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Recordings
      - David Blaine, singer_p_1385; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 54)
      - Magic or Miracle: TV special featuring Uri Geller and Amazing Randi, February 8, 1983; singer_p_0154; VHS; running time 90:00 (Box 37)
      - [James] Randi's reply to [Walter] Uphoff's Letter Responding to His Letter Re: Mind Over Matter Book, 1982/07/11; singer_p_0797; W.V. Grant; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 49)
      - Magic vs. Personality, 1996; singer_p_0312; label on case reads, "Carla/Maria/PS; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
      - Magic, Science, and Health Video to Accompany Magic, Science, and Health: The Aims and Achievements of Medical Anthropology by Robert Anderson, singer_p_0153; label reads, "Harcourt Brace College Publishers"; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 37)
      - Magic: Amazing Randi and the Magic Thumb Trick, Psychic Surgery, singer_p_0156; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 37)
      - Magic: Oprah Show featuring Amazing Randi, October 7, 1986; singer_p_0158; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 37)
      - Magic: Secrets of the Psychics, NOVA episode, 1993; singer_p_0155; label reads, "Part 5 NOVA, Middle March, Psychic Debunker 'Randi'," but after research, the real title is Secrets of the Psychics that was a NOVA episode in 1993; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 37)
      - Magic: The Search for Houdini, October 31, 1987; singer_p_0157; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 37)
  - Mammography
    - Mammogram (Tape 2), singer_p_1553; Mini-cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 43)
    - Mammography Firenze, singer_p_1040; DVD; running time 50:00 (Oversize 5)
    - Mammography Firenze, singer_p_1035; label on case reads, "from 8mm, location, exams, px interviews, [stick figure] group"; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Mammography Firenze Exams, singer_p_1039; DVD; running time 100:00 (Oversize 5)
    - Mammography Firenze Health, singer_p_1037; label on case reads, "Exam machine, waiting room, patients and patients talk, look at x-rays"; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Mammography Firenze Health, singer_p_1038; label on case reads, "Exams, dxs interview, women's group"; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Mammography Firenze Nun, singer_p_1041; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 5)
      A itemized description is listed on case label. "Patients, machine, stand-up x-ray, man (:34), young woman friend (:37), x-ray (:51), older woman (1:01), biopsy (1:21), nuns biopsy (1:26), good biopsy (1:40), woman MD talks to woman (1:52)."
    - Mammography Firenze Nuns Biopsies, singer_p_1036; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Mammography NICU, singer_p_0160; transfer from 8mm; VHS; running time 180:00 (Box 37)
  - Medical anthropology, "A Medical Anthropologist's View of American Shamans," Free Inquiry, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Medical anthropology, "The Missing Link in Medical Anthropology: The Political Economy of Health," Soheir Morsy, 1977 (Box 13)
  - "Medical quacks and quackeries," Francis J. Shepherd, June 1883 (Box 13)
  - Medicinal plants
    - Do Herbs Hold the Secret to Long Life?, 1983 (Box 23)
    - National Trainor's Manual on the Use of Philippine Medicinal Plants, undated (Box 23)
  - Mentalism, Paul Critelli regarding W.V. Grant, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Mental Health
    - A Comprehensive Mental Health Program for the United States Virgin Islands, Aug 1971 (Box 59)
    - Social and community psychiatry, undated (Box 13)
    - Recordings
      - Myth of Mental Illness: Past and Future, 2002; singer_p_1303; label on disc reads, "Oakland University, 2002"; DVD; running time 90:00 (Oversize 6)
      - A Place for Madness, 1994/01/18; singer_p_1173; featured on Frontline on PBS; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 5)
      - A Place for Madness, 1994/01/18; singer_p_1174; featured on Frontline on PBS; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 5)
  - Mental imagery, "The Healing Power of Imagery," Martin L. Rossman, 1987 (Box 13)
  - "Migration and Social Change: A Survey of Indian Communities Overseas," Chandra Jayawardena, American Geographical Society, 1968; cites Singer's work (Box 13)
  - Mind healing
    - Mind as Healer, Mind as Slayer: Belief Systems and Cancer, 1975; singer_p_0861; Audio cassette; running time 55:00 (Box 46)
    - Mind as Healer, Mind as Slayer: Belief Systems and Cancer, 1975; singer_p_0862; Audio cassette; running time 55:00 (Box 46)
    - Mind as Healer, Mind as Slayer: Reorganization in Psychotic Turmoil, 1975; singer_p_0864; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 46)
    - Mind as Healer, Mind as Slayer: Role of Stress in the Psychogenesis of Disease, 1975; singer_p_0863; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 46)
    - Mind as Healer, Mind as Slayer: Uses of Self-Regulation Techniques in Alleviating Stress Disorders, 1975; singer_p_0865; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 46)
  - Miracles, Jul 1997; Life magazine article "Do You Believe in Miracles?" (Box 59)
  - Miracles and Jesus, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1999-2000; clippings (Box 13)
  - Mob therapy, 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Motoyama, Hiroshi
    - The International Association for Religion and Parapsychology newsletter, 1984 (Box 13)
    - Life interviews transcript, 1984 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, 1981 (Box 14)
    - Tamamitsu Shrine rules, undated (Box 14)
  - Native American health
    - American Indian medicine aims to add physicians, improve health, Journal of the American Medical Association, Oct 1985 (Box 14)
    - Pine Ridge snapshots and logs, 1993-1996 (Box 14)
    - Project Report on Orientation of New Professional Staff, Division of Indian Health, 1960; bound (Box 59)
  - Nigeria
    - African Traditional Medicine, Nov 1990 (Box 14)
    - AIDS, Lambo, Chief JO, 1983-1991 (Box 23)
    - AIDS, Okolie, Ben, 1986-1995 (Box 23)
    - Ante-natal and post-natal care, Ajetunmobi, undated (Box 24)
    - Ante-natal care, Olushesi, undated (Box 24)
    - "Ashe, Traditional Religion and Healing in Sub-Saharan Africa and the Diaspora," John Gray, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Beyioku, Chief O.A. Fagbenro, undated (Box 14)
    - Chief L.O. Okolie, 1988-1999 (Box 24)
    - Clinic patients, National Association of Nigerian Refugees, 1973 (Box 24)
    - Durodola, James Dr., 1978-1986 (Box 14)
    - Eme, Chief Dr. N.O., 1991 (Box 14)
    - Esho, Chief F.O., 1978 (Box 14)
    - Faith healers, 1980-1989 (Box 14)
    - Falowo, W.O. Dr., 1977 (Box 14)
    - Folk tales, A.A. IRO, 1974 (Box 24)
    - Godianism, 1973-1975 (Box 14)
    - Integrating Western Orthodox and Indigenous Medicine, Tola Olu Pearce, 1982-1983 (Box 14)
    - Lambo
      - Chief J.O., 1977-1993 (Box 24)
      - Correspondence after Lambo's trip to United States, 1975 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence after Lambo's trip to United States, 1975 (Box 15)
      - Deji, 1993-1994 (Box 24)
    - Lambo lectures, 1-14, undated (Box 15)
    - Leaves are Man's Servants, 1973 (Box 15)
    - Medicinal health, undated (Box 24)
    - Medicinal plants, Akisnaya, 1973 (Box 24)
    - Opara, Theodore M., 1986-1992 (Box 24)
    - Osumah, Dr. J.A., 1973-1980 (Box 24)
    - Peterside, Felix, 1993; business scam (Box 15)
    - "Relationship between nature and medical treatment with special reference to native West African methods," S.T. Leigh Sodipe, undated (Box 15)
    - Singer Emex Foundation, 1999-2001 (Box 15)
    - Singer Emex Foundation, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Smallpox, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
    - Smallpox and WHO, New England Journal of Medicine, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
    - Smallpox, Chief Ozekhome, 1979-1983 (Box 15)
    - Sodipe, Chief R.O. Abimbola, undated; photos (Box 15)
    - Recordings
      - Doctors of Nigeria, 1981; singer_p_0135; clip from NOVA, a PBS TV show; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 35)
      - Doctors of Nigeria, singer_p_1122; DVD; running time 56:00 (Oversize 5)
        A NOVA production that mentions Dr. A. Lambo. Also covers WHO, labo, ESHO, bonesetter, and Aro village. Singer includes note, "Compare with my films on Nigeria."
      - Lambo / WGPR / Daniel DeSole / Philip Singer / Witchcraft / Sex / Mental Illness / Women, singer_p_0810; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 49)
      - Lambo at Merry College, Detroit, Michigan, 1975/03/26; singer_p_0692; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo Class, 1975/03/12; singer_p_0768; label on tape reads, "Cancer, alcohol, OB-GYN, witchcraft, church"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo Interview, Lagos, Traditional Healing, 1973; singer_p_0802; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 49)
      - Lambo Interviews 4 Patients, 1975/03/26; singer_p_0799; text on label reads, "1) alcoholic - obesity, 2) thyroid, 3) nature store, 4) barren"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 49)
      - Lambo Lecture to Hambin Hall, 1975/03/06; singer_p_0764; label on tape reads, "How I became herbolist, IFA and ORUNN, bonesetter (secrets), pregnancy care and abortion, cancer"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo patients, 1975/03/29; singer_p_0613; label on tape reads, "1) Mrs. Timbers and sis, 2) Princers, 3) astrology; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 2)
      - Lambo Patients, 1975/03/29; singer_p_0765; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo Patients, 1975/03/27; singer_p_0771; label on tape reads, "1) Black dry cleaner - impotence and sinus, 2) 'possessed by witch'"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: "Ole Miss," Uses of Herbs, 1975/03/18; singer_p_0721; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: "Ole Miss" Discussion, Health Care in Kenya, Nigerian Health Care Student and Lambo on Traditional Healing, 1975/03/18; singer_p_0723; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Astro-dulitics and Astro-biochemistry, 1975/03/24; singer_p_0693; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Chief At Home of Philip Singer Seeing Patients in Oak Park; "Bad Luck", singer_p_0744; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Diseases and Their Treatment (especially OB-GYN), Anatomy and Diseases, Oakland University, 1975/03/27; singer_p_0724; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Divination and Incantation, Medical Aspects of Astrological Healing, 1975/03/21; singer_p_0767; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: For My People with James Thomas, singer_p_0815; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 49)
      - Lambo: Free Press Interview, 1975/03/20; singer_p_0725; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Healing (Occult) Power of Herbs, 1975/03/13; singer_p_0722; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Newman Show WYYZ (1 and 2), 1975/03/05; singer_p_0697; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Newman Show WYYZ (1 and 2), 1975/03/05; singer_p_0726; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Newman Show WYYZ (3 and 4), 1975/03/05; singer_p_0698; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Newman Show WYYZ (side 3), 1975/03/05; singer_p_0727; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Occult Power of Herbs, 1975/03/17; singer_p_0716; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Lambo: Revolution in Psychology in WHO/Geneva, 1975/11/15; singer_p_0763; interview; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Nigeria, Rafa's Family, Cyber Cafe, singer_p_0435; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
      - Reels I and II: Chief Lambo, Herbal Garden, Village Herbs, Chief Lawson and Patients, singer_p_0792; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 49)
      - Sociology, Authority, Chief Lambo, Occult Power of Herbs Lecture, 1975/03/19; singer_p_0691; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Sociology of Medical Practice Class, Chief Lambo Discussion, 1975/03/25; singer_p_0690; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Nkpora
    - Nkpora agreement, 1973 (Box 24)
    - Recordings
      - Nkpora, 1977/08/16; singer_p_0754; label reads, "KOK healing initiation, paralysis specialization in healing, Philip Singer speech to Nkpora healers"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Nkpora, singer_p_0755; label reads, "Reel 7"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Nkpora, singer_p_0756; label reads, "T-M center, 4 huts; herbal garden; back pain; bone mender"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Nkpora, "Moses," OB-GYN, singer_p_0801; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 49)
      - Nkpora, KOK House, Traditional Healers Land Donation; Village Music, Masked Dancers, 1973; singer_p_0808; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 49)
      - Nkpora, KOK Village Reception, Philip Singer Speech, singer_p_0809; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 49)
      - Nkpora, Traditional Healing, 1977/08/23; singer_p_0783; text on tape reads, "stills/interview with Rural Health Center, Dispenser; V Sater workshop"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Paranormal, The Paranormal as a Paradigm for Traditional Healing, 1975; notes (Box 24)
  - Parenting, "Obedience and Control: Guyanese Parents on Child Rearing Methods," Betty Lanham, undated (Box 15)
  - Peking Union Medical College
    - Peking Union Medical College and Hospital, Traditional and Western Therapies, singer_p_1066; interviews by Philip Singer; DVD; running time 76:00 (Oversize 5)
    - Peking Union Medical College, China, singer_p_1049; interview with herbalists; DVD; running time 76:00 (Oversize 5)
      A handwritten itemized list of contents are on the case. It reads, "Peking Union Medical College. Beijing, traditional medicine, baldness, acupuncture (needling types). Philip Singer at PUMC - interview with patients at PUMC, ACU (Ear) and gallstones - herbs applied to medicines, plant development - herb garden, philosophy of plant usage - anti-aging plant."
    - Peking Union Medical College, China, singer_p_1065; interview with herbalists; DVD; running time 76:00 (Oversize 5)
  - Peru Eduardo the Healer: Hallucinogens
    - Recordings, multiple copies of DVD were kept because content could not be verified
      - Peru Eduardo the Healer: Hallucinogens, singer_p_1204; subtitles; DVD; running time 55:00 (Oversize 6)
      - Peru Eduardo the Healer: Hallucinogens, singer_p_1205; subtitles; DVD; running time 55:00 (Oversize 6)